citizensenergygroup.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy | Citizens Energy Group

| 

## Information Collection and Use 

Citizens Energy Group understands that security and privacy are important issues for visitors to our web site, CITIZENSENERGYGROUP.COM (the "Site") and recognizes our obligations to keep your information secure and confidential. That is why we maintain the standards outlined below to help protect information that personally identifies you. Citizens Energy Group collects information from our users at several different points on our Site. We do this to understand how to better serve our customers. We will not sell, share, or rent this information collected on this Site to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. 

You may be asked to voluntarily provide your name, billing address, credit card information, phone number, utility account number, email address or other personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") to have access to some features of the Site. By using the Site and providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to our use of such information as described in this Policy. You may always refuse to provide your Personal Information, and this may lead to our inability to provide you with certain products or services. We or our business partners may also collect information that is anonymous, such as your IP number (a number used to identify your computer on the Internet) or the type of browser you are using ("Anonymous Information"), through the use of cookies or by other means. We hope that, by using Anonymous Information, we can update the Site to make it more useful to you and other users. We reserve the right to maintain, update, disclose or otherwise use Anonymous Information, without limitation.

Citizens Energy Group uses your Personal Information for the following purposes: to access customer services, respond to or communicate with you, address issues you identify, further improve this Site, forward your e-mail or communication to another agency or entity for appropriate action, to provide Internet security; or to meet legal requirements. Information received by Citizens Energy Group from your communication with this Site, including your e-mail address, is not collected for commercial marketing purposes. 

## **Registration**

We require Citizens Energy Group customers to register so that we may create unique user ID and password (login) information. Residential customers may create their username and password, which allows them to gain access to their personal, protected account information. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password and for restricting access to your computer. You accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password and such use shall be deemed to be use by you. You will ensure that all use of your account fully complies with the Terms and Conditions set forth below. Transfer of the account by you to any other person or entity is prohibited. 

During registration users must submit their contact and account information (such as name, email address and utility account number). This information is used to contact users about the services on our Site for which they have expressed interest so that we may complete their requests. 

## Sharing 

We do not currently share any specific demographic information from this Site with unaffiliated third parties, nor do we provide specific credit or usage information to unaffiliated third party service providers. Citizens Energy Group may provide customer contact information to unaffiliated third party service providers. Such information exists independent from information collected from this Site. This type of information would not be associated with a user's personal information and would not be used to identify an individual person. 

We may work with our business partners who may perform certain functions on our behalf, such as customer billing and payment, sending email messages, managing data, or providing customer service. These business partners have access to your Personal Information only to the extent necessary to perform these specific functions and may not use it for any other purpose. 

In the event that we partner with another party to provide specific services, we will share names and other contact information when the user signs up for these services. These parties cannot use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these specific services. Other than for the specific purposes set forth in this Policy, we will not disclose your Personal Information unless we obtain your prior consent or are legally required to do so. If Citizens Energy Group is involved in the sale of a substantial portion of its business assets, Anonymous or Personal Information maybe among the transferred assets. 

## Supplementation of Information 

In order for this Site to properly fulfill its obligation to our customers, it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from outside sources. For example, in some cases to determine if our customers qualify for one of our services or if a deposit is required, we use their name and social security number to verify their identity and credit history. 

## Cookies 

Citizens Energy Group or a third party advertiser may store or recognize some information on your computer in the form of a "cookie" or similar file that can help us in many ways. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer containing information about the user. By accepting a cookie, the user may save time on our Site, by not have to log in a password more than once. A user that rejects the cookie may still use our Site; however, the user's actions may be limited in some areas of our Site. For example, the user may have to enter contact and billing information repeatedly. Using cookies enables us to target the interests of our users and enhance the experience on the Site. 

## Privacy of Children 

Citizens Energy Group encourages parents and guardians to be aware of and participate in their children's online activities. We strictly adhere to the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and will not knowingly collect, use or disclose Personal Information from any child under the age of 13 in any manner that violates this law.

## Your Opportunity to Opt-out of Email Advertising 

In the event you do not wish to receive promotional email from Citizens Energy Group, follow the opt-out instructions contained within the body of any email message you receive. 

## Log Files 

Web servers create log files in a standard fashion across the Web. We use our web server log information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for the aggregate use of the Site. 

## Site and Service Updates 

Users may receive Site and service announcement updates. Members cannot un-subscribe from these service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to his/her account via email or phone. 

## Links 

This Site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Citizens Energy Group, are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and Citizens Energy Group has not reviewed all of these third party sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. The Policy on our Site applies solely to information collected by the Site. Citizens Energy Group expressly disclaims any liability for any third party's use of your Personal or Anonymous Information obtained through using the third party web site. 

## Security 

Citizens Energy Group will endeavor to take all steps deemed reasonable by the utility to keep secure any Personal Information we hold about you, and to keep this information accurate and up to date. To that end, we have policies and procedures in place to protect the privacy and confidentiality of your Personal Information that we collect and maintain. Citizens Energy Group will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorized access to your Personal Information. 

## Contacting CITIZENSENERGYGROUP.COM or Modifying Your Personal Information 

If you have any questions or comments about this Policy, please contact us by email at: [CustomerCare@CitizensEnergyGroup.com](mailto:CustomerCare@CitizensEnergyGroup.com). Please provide a concise communication with complete information, including your contact information. 

## Notification of Changes 

We may modify this Policy at any time and, accordingly, we urge you to frequently review the Policy. If changes are made, the changes will be posted on our Site so our users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and how under certain circumstances, we may disclose it. If at any point we decide to use Personal Information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email message. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the Policy under which the information was collected.
